<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--2019-01-30 ebb: EXAM FILE. 
    The schema association line below points to the original exam's Relax NG file. 
    Download both the XML and the Relax NG to save in your own space, and rename according to our filenaming conventions. 
    You should comment out the line below and **reassociate** this XML with your own renamed schema file to check and make sure you are correcting its mistakes. 
    You'll be submitting your new schema file and this XML file on Courseweb. -->
<?xml-model href="RNGtest2019.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<xml>
    <docInfo>
        <title>XML is 20</title>
        <subtitle>Tim Bray on XML's 20th birthday</subtitle>
        <author id="Bray_Tim">Tim Bray</author>
        <publication type="digital" target="https://www.xml.com/articles/2018/02/10/xml-20/"
            >XML.com</publication>
        <pubDate when="2018-02-10"/>
        <copyright>Article contents © 2018 Tim Bray</copyright>
    </docInfo>
    <body>
        <p><quote source="Beatles">“It was twenty years ago today/Sergeant Pepper taught the band to
                play…</quote>. Actually, it was <duration quantity="21.5" unit="year">21½ years ago
                today</duration> that <persName>Jon Bosak</persName> pulled together the original
                <orgName>XML Working Group</orgName>. But yes, it was <event>on <date
                    when="1998-02-10">February 10, 1998</date> that <codeSpec>XML 1.0</codeSpec> was
                released to the world</event>. Which is worth talking about.</p>
        <p>It turns out that if you follow the pointers back, the original <codeSpec>XML 1.0
                Specification</codeSpec> is still out there; <rs type="person" ref="Bray_Tim">my
                fingers</rs> were the last to touch that document. The history of how XML came to be
            has been told at great length elsewhere, as have the details about <date
                when="1998-02-10">that February 10th</date>, so there’s no need to revisit.</p>
        <sectionHead>What matters?</sectionHead>
        <p><date when="2018">Twenty years later</date>, it seems obvious that the most important
            thing about <codeSpec>XML</codeSpec> is that it was the first. The first data format
            that anyone could pack anything up into, send across the network to anywhere, and unpack
            on the other end, without asking anyone’s permission or paying for software, or for the
            receiver to have to pay attention to what the producer thought they’d produced it for or
            what it meant.</p>
        <p>That comment about software highlights another thing that matters: These days, nobody in
            their wildest dreams would consider designing a data format without also shipping
            open-source software to do something useful with it. But <duration quantity="10"
                unit="year">in 2008</duration>, it was pretty noteworthy that <event>by <date
                    when="2008-02-10">February tenth</date>, there were already several
                    <software>open-source parsers</software> available off-the-shelf</event>.</p>
        <p>The second thing that mattered was the recognition that <catchPhrase>documents are
                data</catchPhrase> and deserve to be treated with respect, with grown-up software,
            just like the rows and columns in <docFormat>spreadsheets</docFormat> and
                <software>databases</software>. <date when="2018">Today</date>, serious documents —
                <docGenre type="medical">medical records</docGenre>, the <docGenre type="legal">Legislation of the United States of
                America</docGenre> — live in XML and there’s really no other good choice.</p>
        <p>Now, the mirror image of that statement is that <catchPhrase type="inverse">you can treat
                data records as documents</catchPhrase>. People did a lot of that with
                <codeSpec>XML</codeSpec> just because there was no other alternative and, well…
            while it worked, you could do better, and in fact we have done better, for weak values
            of “better”. I wonder if we’ll ever do better still? As the editor of the <codeSpec>IETF
                JSON RFCs</codeSpec>, I’m a pessimist.</p>
        <sectionHead>It’s been OK</sectionHead>
        <p>Seriously; <codeSpec>XML</codeSpec> made a lot of things possible that previously
            weren’t. It has extended the lifetime of big chunks of our intellectual and legal
            heritage. It’s created a lot of interesting jobs and led to the production of a lot of
            interesting software. We could have done better, but you always could have done
            better.</p>
        <p>
            <event when="--02-10">Happy birthday!</event>
        </p>

    </body>
</xml>
