<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="../../../Downloads/hill_09-11_xml-5.rnc"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="../../../Downloads/hill_09-11_xml-5.rnc"?>
<?xml-model href="../../../Downloads/hill_09-11_xml-5.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<sonnets lines ="14" rhymescheme="ABABCDCDEFEFGG" language ="English" author ="William Shakespeare">
    <sonnet n = "1">
        <line n="1">FROM fairest creatures we desire increase,</line>
        <line n="2">That thereby beauty's rose might never die,</line>
        <line n="3">But as the riper should by time decease,</line>
        <line n="4">His tender heir might bear his memory:</line>
        <line n="5">But thou, contracted to thine own bright eyes,</line>
        <line n="6">Feed'st thy light'st flame with self-substantial fuel,</line>
        <line n="7">Making a famine where abundance lies,</line>
        <line n="8">Thyself thy foe, to thy sweet self too cruel.</line>
        <line n="9">Thou that art now the world's fresh ornament</line>
        <line n="10">And only herald to the gaudy spring,</line>
        <line n="11">Within thine own bud buriest thy content</line>
        <line n="12">And, tender churl, makest waste in niggarding.</line>
        <line n="13">Pity the world, or else this glutton be,</line>
        <line n="14">To eat the world's due, by the grave and thee.</line>
    </sonnet>
    <sonnet n="2">
        <line n="1">When forty winters shall beseige thy brow,</line>
        <line n="2">And dig deep trenches in thy beauty's field,</line>
        <line n="3">Thy youth's proud livery, so gazed on now,</line>
        <line n="4">Will be a tatter'd weed, of small worth held:</line>
        <line n="5">Then being ask'd where all thy beauty lies,</line>
        <line n="6">Where all the treasure of thy lusty days,</line>
        <line n="7">To say, within thine own deep-sunken eyes,</line>
        <line n="8">Were an all-eating shame and thriftless praise.</line>
        <line n="9">How much more praise deserved thy beauty's use,</line>
        <line n="10">If thou couldst answer 'This fair child of mine</line>
        <line n="11">Shall sum my count and make my old excuse,'</line>
        <line n="12">Proving his beauty by succession thine!</line>
        <line n="13">This were to be new made when thou art old,</line>
        <line n="14">And see thy blood warm when thou feel'st it cold.</line>
    </sonnet>
</sonnets>